grade_7_part_1 = {
    "Negative numbers: addition and subtraction": [
        {
            "Addition and subtraction with negatives": {
            "Definition": "One great thing about working with negatives is that we can rewrite all subtraction as addition of the opposite.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Zombies lose limbs. Mutants grow limbs. Mutant-zombies do both. Today, a certain mutant-zombie grew 5 limbs, lost 12 limbs, and grew another 2 limbs. What is the change in number of limbs the mutant-zombie has compared to yesterday?",
                        "Answer": "We can rewrite the expressions to show the change in the mutant-zombie's limb:\nGrew 5 limbs: +5,\nLost 12 limbs: -12,\nGrew another 2 limbs: +2.\nIn total, the change is: 5 + (-12) + 2 = (5 + 2) + (-12) = 7 - 12 = -5.\nSo the mutant has lost 5 limbs.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        },
        {
            "One-step equations with negatives (add and subtract)": {
            "Definition": "One great thing about working with negatives is that we can rewrite all subtraction as addition of the opposite.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Lucas has painted a fraction of a paper on red color.\nUnfortunately, his brother, Ness, tried to be creative and painted back 4/7 of the paper on blue.\nNote that all the area Ness painted is previously in red.\nIf currently 3/16 of the paper is in red, what proportion of the paper Lucas has painted red beforehand?",
                        "Answer": "Let the fraction of paper that Lucas painted beforehand be g.\nWe can create an equation: g + (-4/7) = 3/16.\nSolving this equation, we obtain: g = 3/16 - (-4/7) = 3/16 + 4/7 = 85/112.\nSo Lucas has previously painted 85/112 of the paper in red.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
        }
    ],
     "Negative numbers: multiplication and division":[
        {
            "Multiply and divide negative numbers": {
            "Definition": "When we multiply or divide two negative numbers, the result is a positive number. This might seem strange at first, but it's important to remember that a negative sign in math is really just an instruction to change the direction of a number on a number line. So when we multiply or divide two negative numbers, we're reversing the direction twice, which brings us back to a positive number.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "After being exposed to an electromagnetic shrinking machine, Joe's height decreased by 120 cm over 1.5 seconds. His height decreased by the same amount each second. How much did Joe's height change each second?",
                        "Answer": "Joe's height change after 1.5 seconds is -120 cm.\nSo each second, Joe's height change is: (-120) / 1.5 = -80 cm.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Fractions, decimals and percentage":[
        {
            "Converting fractions to decimals":{
            "Definition": "A terminating decimal is one that ends. A repeating decimal, on the other hand, goes on forever.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Tao has 200 g of butter and would love to share it equally to his 6 friends.\nWhat is the amount of butter that each friend receive (in grams)? Write you answer as a decimal expression.",
                        "Answer": "Each friend would receive 200 / 6 = 33.\overline{3} grams of butter.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Percent":{
            "Definition": "To find the percent increase or decrease, we need two numbers: the original number and the new number. We divide the difference between the two by the original number. We'll get our value in decimal or fraction form, and we can rewrite it as a percent from there.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Cody was 165cm tall on the first day of school this year, which was 10% taller than he was on the first day of school last year. How tall was Cody on the first day of school last year?",
                        "Answer": "Cody's height on the first day of school this year was 10% taller than his height on the first day of school last year. He still had all (100%) of last year's height plus 10% more.\nThis year, he was 100%+10%=110% of his height from last year.\nTo find Cody's previous height, we need to answer, 165cm is 110% of what height?\nWe can just divide 165cm by 110% and get 150cm.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Rational number":{
            "Definition": "A rational number is a number that can be express as the ratio of two integers.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Sathish is going on a 2100-kilometer road trip with 2 friends, whom he will pick up 150 kilometers after he begins the trip and drop off when there are 150 kilometers remaining. The car consumes 6 liters of gas for every 100 kilometers, and gas costs $1.20 per liter. Sathish will pay for all of the gas when he is alone in the car, but he and his friends will split the cost evenly when they are together. How much will Sathish pay for gas?",
                        "Answer": "Sathish travels 300km alone, so he uses 300 / 100 * 6 = 18 liters of gas when he is alone.\nGas costs $1.20 per liter, so he pays 1.20 * 18 = 21.60 dollars for gas when he is alone.\nThere are 3 people in the car for 2100 - 300 = 1800 km.\nThey use 1800 / 100 * 6 = 108 liters of gas, and pay a total of 108 * 1.20 = 129.60 dollars.\nThe money is split between 3 people, so each of them pay 129.60 / 3 = 43.20 dollars at that time.\nIn total, Sathish pays 43.20 + 21.60 = 64.80 dollars for gas.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Rates and proportional relationships":[
        {
            "Rates with fractions":{
            "Definition": "A constant of proportionality is a number that relates two quantities in a proportional relationship. For example, if we say that y is proportional to x, we might write the equation y = kx, where k is the constant of proportionality. The constant of proportionality is another name for the unit rate.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Robert climbed 775 steps in 12 1/2 minutes. How many steps did he average per minute?",
                        "Answer": "To find steps per minute, we divide total steps by minutes: 775 / (12 1/2) = 775 / (25 / 2) = 775 * 2 / 25 = 1550 / 25 = 62.\nSo Robert climbed 62 steps per minute.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Proportion word problems":{
            "Definition": "To write a proportion, we set two rates equal to each other. For example, we might say 2/4 = 6/12. Solving a proportion just means finding the missing value in the proportion.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Kwesi is putting on sunscreen. He uses 3 ml to cover 45 cm^2 of his skin. He wants to know how many milliliters of sunscreen (g) he needs to cover 240 cm^2 of his skin. He assumes the relationship between milliliters of sunscreen and area is proportional. How many milliliters of sunscreen does Kwesi need?",
                        "Answer": "We can set up an equation to show the proportion of sunscreen to skin area: 3/45 = g/240.\nSolving for g, we obtain: g = 240 * 3 / 45 = 240 / 15 = 16.\nSo Kwesi needs 16 ml of sunscreen.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Equations of proportional relationships":{
            "Definition": "There are a few ways we can tell if two quantities are proportional to each other. We might see that the ratio between the two quantities is always the same, or we might see that a graph of the two quantities forms a straight line through the origin (the point where both x and y are equal to 0).",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Lulu the Lucky puts chests of gems into her treasure vault. Each chest holds the same number of gems. The list below shows the number of gems Lulu received from three different adventures and the number of chests she needed to hold the gems.\nAdventure A: Number of gems: 600, Number of chests: 2.\nAdventure B: Number of gems: 1500, Number of chests: 5.\nAdventure C: Number of gems: 4800, Number of chests: 16.\nWrite an equation to describe the relationship between g, the number of gems, and c, the number of chests.",
                        "Answer": "From the list, we see that we can multiply the number of chests by 300 to get the number of gems in each adventure.\nSo the constant of proportionality is 300, which means that the equation is: g = 300c.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Expressions, equations and inequalities":[
        {
            "Equivalent expressions":{
            "Definition": "The commutative property of addition tells us that we can rearrange the order of the terms we're adding together without changing the sum. This is really helpful when we want to combine like terms in an algebraic expression that also has unlike terms.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Simplify and create an equivalent expression: 1/7 - 3(3/7 n - 2/7).",
                        "Answer": "Use the distributive property to multiply the -3 into the parentheses and get: 1/7 - 9/7 n + 6/7 = 1 - 9/7 n.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Interpreting linear expressions":{
            "Definition": "A linear expression is built out of three main parts: the variable, the coefficient, and the constant. When we use a linear expression to represent a real-world situation, each part of the expression has a different meaning. The variable is the part of the expression that can change. The coefficient is the number in front of the variable. The constant is the number that doesn't change, no matter what the variable is.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Grandma Gertrude gave 13 pieces of jewelry and Grandma Fien gave y pieces of jewelry to the Carlson sisters to divide evenly among themselves. There are 5 Carlson sisters. How many pieces of jewelry did each sister receive?",
                        "Answer": "The total amount of jewelry given to 5 sisters is 13 + y pieces.\nSo each sister receives (13 + y) / 5 pieces of jewelry.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Two-step equations":{
            "Definition": "A two-step equation is an algebraic equation you can solve in two steps. Once you've solved it, you've found the value of the variable that makes the equation true.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "In winter, the price of apples suddenly went up by $0.75 per pound. Sam bought 3 pounds of apples at the new price for a total of $5.88.\nFind the original price per pound.",
                        "Answer": "Let p be the original price per pound of apples. The new price is p + 0.75 dollars per pound.\nSam bought 3 pounds of apples, so Sam's total cost was 3(p+0.75).\nSince his total cost was $5.88, we have the equation: 3(p + 0.75) = 5.88.\nSolving this equation: p + 0.75 = 5.88 / 3 = 1.96, so p = 1.21.\nThe original price of the apples was $1.21 per pound.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "One-step inequality":{
            "Definition": "We solve inequalities in the same way that we solve two-step equations, except that we need to remember one rule: if we multiply or divide both sides by a negative number, we need to reverse the inequality sign.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A contractor is purchasing some stone tiles for a new patio. Each tile costs $3, and he wants to spend less than $1000. The size of each tile is 1 square foot.\nHow large the stone patio can be?",
                        "Answer": "Let x be the number of tiles purchased.\nThe total cost is then 3x dollars.\nSince the contractor wants to spend less than $1000, we obtain the inequality 3x <= 1000.\nSolving the inequality, we see that x <= 1000/3.\nSo the size of the patio is at most 1000/3 = 333 1/3 square feet.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Two-step inequality":{
            "Definition": "We solve inequalities in the same way that we solve two-step equations, except that we need to remember one rule: if we multiply or divide both sides by a negative number, we need to reverse the inequality sign.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Mrs. Morton has a special reward system for her class. When all her students behave well, she rewards them by putting 3 marbles into a marble jar. When the jar has 100 or more marbles, the students have a party. Right now, the jar has 24 marbles. Will the students have a party if Mrs. Morton rewards them 31 additional times?",
                        "Answer": "Let r be the number of additional times that Mrs. Morton would need to reward them before throwing a party.\nThen the total number of marbles in the marble jar would be: 24 + 3r.\nSince there needs to be at least 100 marbles, we obtain the inequality 24 + 3r >= 100.\nWe can solve the inequality by subtracting both sides by 24, then dividing both sides by 3, and obtain: r >= (100 - 24) / 3 = 25 1/3.\nSo Mrs. Morton only needs to reward them 26 additional times, which is smaller than 31.\nIt means that the students will have a party after 31 additional times rewarded.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ]
}

grade_7_part_2 = {
    "Geometry":[
        {
            "Circumference of circles":{
            "Definition": "The circumference is the distance around a circle (its perimeter!). The circumference C of any circle is calculated by the following formula: C = \pi d, with d being the diameter.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Bilal's fishing line was on a spool with a radius of 4 cm. Suddenly, a fish pulled on the line, and the spool spun 16 times before Bilal began to reel in the fish. What is the distance the fish pulled the fishing line? Round your answer to the nearest cm.",
                        "Answer": "Each time the spool spun, the fish pulled a length of fishing line equal to the circumference of the spool.\nWe can use the formula C=2 \pi R (R being the radius) to find the circumference of the spool.\nSince R = 4 cm, the circumference of the spool is 8 \pi cm.\nSince the spool spun 16 times, the total distance the fish pulled the fishing line is: 16 * 8 \pi = 128 \pi \approx 402.\nSo the fish pulled the fishing line for approximately 402 cm.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Area of circles":{
            "Definition": "To find the area of a circle, we can use the following formula: Area of circle = \pi * radius^2.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "A baker uses a coffee mug with a diameter of 8 cm to cut out circular cookies from a big sheet of cookie dough. What is the area A of each cookie? Give your answer in terms of pi.",
                        "Answer": "The radius of the circular cookie in 8 / 2 = 4 cm.\nUsing the formula, we get the area of the circle: \pi * radius^2 = 16 \pi cm^2.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Vertical, complementary, and supplementary angles":{
            "Definition": "Complementary angles are two angles with a sum of 90 \degree. Supplementary angles are two angles with a sum of 180 \degree.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "\angle A and \angle B are complementary angles. \angle, a measures 59 \degree. What is the measure of \angle B?",
                        "Answer": "The sum of measures of two angles is 90 \degree since they are complementary.\nSo the measure of \angle B is 90 \degree - 59 \degree = 21 \degree.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Triangle inequality theorem":{
            "Definition": "In a triangle, the length of a side is always smaller than the sum of length of the 2 other sides.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Given a triangle ABC with AB = 8.0 cm, AC = 8.8 cm.\nFind the possible range of length of BC.",
                        "Answer": "By the triangle inequality, we can obtain the following inequalities:\nAB + AC > BC. This means that 8.0 + 8.8 > BC, so BC < 16.8.\nAB + BC > AC. This means that 8.0 + BC > 8.8, so BC > 0.8.\nAC + BC > AB. This means that 8.8 + BC > 8.0, which is trivial.\nSo in conclusion, we have 0.8 cm < BC < 16.8 cm.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Scale drawing":{
            "Definition": "Scale copies and scale drawings are smaller or larger versions of a shape or object, but with the same proportions.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Polygon C has an area of 7 square units. Jennie drew a scaled version of Polygon C and labeled it Polygon D. Polygon D has an area of 28 square units. What scale factor did Jennie use to go from Polygon C to Polygon D?",
                        "Answer": "The area of Polygon D is 4 times greater than the area of Polygon C.\nThe area of a polygon created with a scale factor of x is x^2 times larger than the original polygon.\nSo we need to find x > 0 such that x^2 = 4.\nSolve for x, we get the scale factor being 2.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ],
    "Statistics and probability": [
        {
            "Basic probability":{
            "Definition": "Basic probability is the chance of something happening, based on what we know or assume. To find the probability of any event, we need to know how many possible outcomes there are, and how many of those outcomes are favorable to the event. When all of the outcomes are equally likely, then the probability of an event is the ratio of the number of favorable outcomes to the number of possible outcomes.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "The probability of it snowing in Eastern Canada tomorrow is 0.4. The probability of it snowing in Western Canada tomorrow is 2/5. Which of the events mentioned is more likely?",
                        "Answer": "Both of the events have the same probability of happening since 0.4 = 2/5.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Probability models":{
            "Definition": "A probability model is a way of showing all the possible outcomes of a situation and their probabilities. We can make a probability model by using a table, a list, or a tree diagram.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Mekala has an MP3 player called the Jumble. The Jumble randomly selects a song for the user to listen to. Mekala's Jumble has 4 techno songs, 2 country songs, and 3 jazz songs on it. Mekala plans to listen to 270 songs. What is your best estimation of the number of country songs that Mekala would listen to?",
                        "Answer": "We can assume that each song has an equal chance to be played, which means that it will be played 1 / (4 + 2 + 3) = 1/9 of the times.\nThere are 2 country songs, which means that in total, the country songs would be played about 2/9 of the times.\nSo, if Mekala plans to listen to 270 songs, she would listen to about 270 * 2 / 9 = 60 country songs.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Compound events and sample spaces":{
            "Definition": "A compound event is an event that involves two or more simple events. For example, rolling a die and tossing a coin is a compound event.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Marvin lives in Stormwind City and works as an engineer in the city of Ironforge. In the morning, he has 3 transportation options (teleport, ride a dragon, or walk) to work, and in the evening he has the same 3 choices for his trip home. If Marvin randomly chooses his method of travel in the morning and in the evening, what is the probability that he teleports at least once per day?",
                        "Answer": "In the event that Marvin does not teleport at all in a day, there are 2 options of transport in the morning (ride a dragon and walk), and also 2 options of transport in the evening.\nThe chance that he would not be teleporting in the morning is 2/3, and the chance that he would not be teleporting in the evening is also 2/3.\nSo the chance that he would not be teleporting at all in a day is 2/3 * 2/3 = 4/9.\nWe take the complement of it, and get 5/9 as the chance that Marvin would teleport at least once.\nWe can also list all 9 posible outcomes and count the number of times that Marvin teleports at least once.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        },
        {
            "Comparing and sampling populations":{
            "Definition": "Sampling populations is the process of selecting a small group of people or things from a larger group, called a population, and using the sample to learn something about the population.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Bounce Club surveyed a random sample of 55 of their members about their favorite type of music. Of the members surveyed, 22 said that jazz is their favorite type of music. There are 422 Bounce Club members. Based on the data, what is the most reasonable estimate for the number of Bounce Club members whose favorite type of music is jazz music?",
                        "Answer": "According to the survey, about 22/55 = 2/5 of the members of the club have jazz as their favorite type of music.\nIn total, there are 422 Bounce Club members, so the number of members whose favorite type of music is jazz is about 422 * 2 / 5 = 168.8 \approx 169 members.",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 3
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,   
            }
        }
    ]
}